# Hossein MohammadiPour

Software Engineer - Node.js Developer

+46 733094215 | me@hossein.link | linkedin.com/in/hosseinDotLink | github.com/hosseinDotLink

### **Summary**

Currently working as a back-end developer at PinMeTo AB. Writing computer apps for over 6 years and specialising in Back-End development for over 3 years. Super-nerd who enjoys customising the development environment and loves JavaScript, unit testing and GNU/Linux. Interested in devising a better solving method for challenging tasks and learning the latest technologies and tools as needed.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## PinMeTo - Malmo, Sweden

Software Developer

Sep 2022 – Present

Onboarding and starting ::)

#### Sell Staged - London, United Kingdom

Node.js Developer

Aug 2021 – Aug 2022

- Communicated with 5 teams to develop and implement programs in 3 different countries (Australia, the United Kingdom, and Iran).
- My favorite project is <u>Safegram</u>, which uses blockchain technology to ensure the safe transfer of large amounts of money around the globe.
- Increased response speed (200%) by making changes to the database schema and adding Redis to cache emergency information.

### Projects:

- Safegram: Sending money to over 200 countries & territories through the mobile app or online payable with crypto-currencies / Node.js - Express JS - MongoDB - Redis - azure-server - CoinPayments - gitlab CI/CD
- Qikr: Online taxi service in London / Node.js Express JS MongoDB Redis azure-server Stripe payment - Microservices - Socket.io
- 3. <u>Jiffy-App</u>: Supermarket in Sydney of Australia / Node.js Express JS MongoDB azure-server Braintree payment Twilio
- 4. Youthhood 2 Adulthood (Y2A): Platform that intended to educate and empower young people ages 15 to 25 within the UK. / Node.js Express JS MongoDB Redis azure-server Stripe payment
- 5. POT : POT is a football analysis and prediction application / Node.js Express JS MongoDB Redis azure-server Docker

## Al Yasin holding - Tehran, Iran

Node.js Developer

Dec 2020 – Aug 2021

- Surveyed more than 1500 businesses in T to find a better user experience in accessing and finding them.
- Participate in AGILE project methodology and conform to coding standards including git workflow and code reviews.

### Karina Pars - Mashhad, Iran

Back-End Developer (Django, flask, and Node.js)

Jan 2018 - Oct 2019

- Development of basic payment gateway infrastructure with higher speed, security, and accuracy.
- 33% increase in company resources due to payment gateway performance.

### **Freelancer**

Sep 2016 - Mar 2018

Last update: 29 Jan 2022

- Design or develop software systems with different languages and technologies (environments and frameworks).
- Advised customers about or performed maintenance on software systems.
- Learned Back-End technologies and system architectures.

### Aria khorshid - Mashhad, Iran

Electronic Components Developer

Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

• Learned how to develop microcontrollers, such as the AVR or Atmega series, and make LED scrolling/fixed panels.

### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Computer Engineering – University of Torbat Heydarieh, Iran

2015 - 2019

### **Skills**

JavaScript - Typescript - Node.js - Express JS - NoSQL/SQL based databases - Basics of Front-End development - git - gitlab CI/CD - Software architectures and Design patterns - TDD - Agile

Last update: 29 Jan 2022